<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Ferry Proxy</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Ferry Proxy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://ferryproxy.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/roadmap/</guid><description>Roadmap # This document outlines some goals, non-goals, and future aspirations for Ferry as a project. DONE # Engage encryption Use Ferryctl alone to configure service mapping between clusters without the Controller Support multi-level proxy Support for mcs api Load balancing TODO # Support complete uninstallation of itself and cleanup Monitor status and display in Hub&amp;rsquo;s status Adapting to the ecosystem Multi-replicas tunnels for a single Hub SSH-via-QUIC: QUIC is used to replace TCP in SSH, no need to reconnect after an IP change, expect better performance Support for any device to actively connect and join as a hub, SDK and Binary provided Support for two hubs without public IPs to connect directly via UDP p2p after control plane collocation Failover Proximity access Access control IDEA # Provide an view of traffic flow and service performance Support UDP of Service Suggesting # If we&amp;rsquo;ve missed something that would make Ferry more useful to you, please let us know.</description></item><item><title>Control Plane Unreachable</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/control-plane-unreachable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/control-plane-unreachable/</guid><description>Control Plane Unreachable # Prepare at least two clusters for demonstration
Can be a cluster of one node or a cluster of Kind but at least two.
Preparation # Preparation
Initialize Control Plane Cluster # # execute on control plane ferryctl control-plane init --control-plane-reachable=false Join a Data Plane Cluster # Define which Data Plane Cluster needs to be joined # # execute on Control Plane Cluster ferryctl control-plane join cluster-1 &amp;#34;--data-plane-tunnel-address=${HOST_IP}:31001&amp;#34; --control-plane-reachable=false --data-plane-tunnel-address Specify the address of the Data Plane Cluster Tunnel for the Control Plane Cluster --control-plane-reachable Specify whether the Data Plane Cluster is reachable Need handshake</description></item><item><title>Data Plane Unreachable</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/data-plane-unreachable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/data-plane-unreachable/</guid><description>Data Plane Unreachable # Prepare at least two clusters for demonstration
Can be a cluster of one node or a cluster of Kind but at least two.
Preparation # Preparation
Initialize Control Plane Cluster # # execute on control plane ferryctl control-plane init Join a Data Plane Cluster # Define which Data Plane Cluster needs to be joined # # execute on Control Plane Cluster ferryctl control-plane join cluster-1 &amp;#34;--control-plane-tunnel-address=${HOST_IP}:31000&amp;#34; --data-plane-reachable=false --control-plane-tunnel-address Specify the address of the Control Plane Cluster Tunnel for the Data Plane Cluster --data-plane-reachable Specify whether the Data Plane Cluster is reachable Need handshake</description></item><item><title>Default Example</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/default/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/default/</guid><description>Default Example # Prepare at least two clusters for demonstration
Can be a cluster of one node or a cluster of Kind but at least two.
Download ferryctl # ferryctl is the installation and operation tool for ferry
A ferryctl needs to be installed for each cluster&amp;rsquo;s control node
https://github.com/ferryproxy/ferry/releases
Preparation # Preparation
Join a Data Plane Cluster # Define which Data Plane Cluster needs to be joined # # execute on Control Plane Cluster ferryctl control-plane join cluster-1 Need handshake</description></item><item><title>Forward Local Port to Cluster</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/forward-dial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/forward-dial/</guid><description>Forward Local Port to Cluster # Preparation # Preparation
Forward Local Port to Cluster # ferryctl local forward dial &amp;lt;local address port&amp;gt; &amp;lt;remote service port&amp;gt; ferryctl local forward dial 0.0.0.0:18080 web-0.test.svc:80 All accesses to port 127.0.0.1:18080 are forwarded to port web-0.test.svc:80
Sample</description></item><item><title>Forward Service to Local Port</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/forward-listen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/forward-listen/</guid><description>Forward Service to Local Port # Preparation # Preparation
Forward Service to Local Port # ferryctl local forward listen &amp;lt;remote service port&amp;gt; &amp;lt;local address port&amp;gt; ferryctl local forward listen local.test.svc:80 127.0.0.1:28080 All accesses on web-0.test.svc:80 in the cluster are forwarded to the local port 127.0.0.1:28080
Sample</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/glossary/</guid><description>Glossary # API server # Also known as:kube-apiserver
The API server is a component of the Kubernetes control plane that exposes the Kubernetes API. The API server is the front end for the Kubernetes control plane
Cluster # A set of worker machines, called nodes, that run containerized applications. Every cluster has at least one worker node.
Controller # In Kubernetes, controllers are control loops that watch the state of your cluster, then make or request changes where needed.</description></item><item><title>Handshake</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/handshake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/handshake/</guid><description>handshake # Some commands need to notify both clusters of this behavior called handshaking
Automatic # If two clusters can be connected at the same time
KUBECONFIG specifies the kubeconfig file for the current cluster
FERRY_PEER_KUBECONFIG specifies the kubeconfig file of the peer cluster
Manual # If you cannot connect to both clusters at the same time
First response # After the command is executed in the current cluster, a response is copied to the peer cluster to execution</description></item><item><title>Hub</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/hub/</guid><description>Hub # Hub CR defines a Hub, which is the address to communicate with other Hubs, For now only one cluster is supported, in the future it will be added to support any possible device as a Hub, even your laptop
Hub provides the basis for RoutePolicy CR and Route CR calculations
apiVersion: traffic.ferryproxy.io/v1alpha2 kind: Hub spec: gateway: # Reachable indicates that this Hub is reachable reachable: true # Address is the address of this Hub, used when Reachable is true address: 1.</description></item><item><title>Manual Mapping Service</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/examples/manual/</guid><description>Manual Mapping Service # Why this is needed # In some cluster unreachability scenarios, the apiserver address of the data plane needs to be exposed to the control plane in advance so that the control plane can access the apiserver of the data plane.
The routing rules configured by this feature are not controlled by the ferry-controller.
Preparation # Preparation
Manual Mapping Service # Define exporting a service from another cluster # ferryctl local manual import --reachable=true &amp;#34;--tunnel-address=${HOST_IP}:31000&amp;#34; --export-host-port=web-1.</description></item><item><title>MCS API</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/mcs_api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/mcs_api/</guid><description>MCS API # This is the set of APIs defined in [kubernetes-sigs/mcs-api][1
Ferry will get the ServiceExport and ServiceImport CRs from all Hub CRs clusters that have the mcs.traffic.ferryproxy.io/service=enabled label. Get their ServiceExport and ServiceImport CRs, convert them to RoutePolicy CR, so that they are compatible with the mcs api</description></item><item><title>Preparation</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/preparation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/preparation/</guid><description>Download ferryctl # ferryctl is the installation and maintenance tool for Ferry
You need to install ferryctl for each cluster
https://github.com/ferryproxy/ferry/releases
Install Tunnel # Tunnel needs to be installed for each cluster
Clusters that support LoadBalancer # As in each public cloud environment
ferryctl data-plane init --tunnel-service-type=LoadBalancer Other # such as Kind or private cloud environments
will use NodePort to expose port 31087 by default</description></item><item><title>Route</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/route/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/route/</guid><description>Route # Route CR Define a routing rules for individual services between hubs
apiVersion: traffic.ferryproxy.io/v1alpha2 kind: Route spec: export: hubName: cluster-1 service: namespace: default name: app-1 import: hubName: cluster-0 service: namespace: default name: app-1 The example CR describes Hub cluster-1 exporting Service app-1.default, importing it in Hub cluster-0 and naming it app-1.default The name and namespace of the import and export do not have to be the same</description></item><item><title>Route Policy</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/route_policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/crd/route_policy/</guid><description>Route Policy # RoutePolicy is used to define generic composite routing rules, which will eventually convert to Route CR
Explicit Route # One-to-one import # apiVersion: traffic.ferryproxy.io/v1alpha2 kind: RoutePolicy spec: exports: - hubName: cluster-1 service: namespace: default name: app-1 imports: - hubName: cluster-0 service: namespace: default name: app-1 This is a CR equivalent to the Route CR example
Import from multiple Hubs # apiVersion: traffic.ferryproxy.io/v1alpha2 kind: RoutePolicy spec: exports: - hubName: cluster-1 service: namespace: default name: app-1 - hubName: cluster-2 service: namespace: default name: app-1 imports: - hubName: cluster-0 service: namespace: default name: app-1 This routing rule generates two Route CR, app-1.</description></item><item><title>Technology Principle</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/principle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/principle/</guid><description>Technology Principle # Communication and penetration # Ferry-Tunnel uses the capabilities of the ssh protocol for communication and penetration between Ferry-Tunnel
The following capabilities are primarily used
direct-tcpip tcpip-forward direct-streamlocal streamlocal-forward There are two core points
Listen to a local port, connect to the Ferry-Tunnel on the other side, and forward all connections through it Connecting to the peer Ferry-Tunnel and listening to a port, and forwarding connections from the listening port to the local Service Discovery # Each exported service port will be assigned a port in the Ferry-Tunnel of the imported cluster</description></item><item><title>With Service Mesh</title><link>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/with-service-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferryproxy.io/docs/user/with-service-mesh/</guid><description>With Service Mesh # As verified in Istio, Ferry fits perfectly as long as Sidecar is not injected into the ferry-tunnel</description></item></channel></rss>