<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Ferry Proxy</title><link>https://ferry.zsm.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Ferry Proxy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://ferry.zsm.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/developer/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/developer/roadmap/</guid><description>Roadmap # First roadmap 🎉
This document outlines some goals, non-goals, and future aspirations for Ferry as a project.
Requirements
Authentication between Tunnels #36</description></item><item><title>Join Mode</title><link>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/user/join-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/user/join-mode/</guid><description>Join Mode # &amp;gt; ferryctl control-plane pre-join --help Generate command for data plane join Need to copy the generated command to run on the data plane. Usage: ferryctl control-plane pre-join [command] Aliases: pre-join, p, pj, join, j Available Commands: direct Clusters can reach each other tunnel Control plane can't touch the data plane Flags: -h, --help help for pre-join There are currently two ways to join
direct tunnel direct # It is suitable for the case where the network between clusters is interoperable, and there is no need to do penetration or proxy operations.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/user/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ferry.zsm.io/docs/user/quick-start/</guid><description>Quick Start # Prepare at least two clusters for demonstration
Can be a cluster of one node or a cluster of Kind but at least two.
Download ferryctl # ferryctl is the installation and operation tool for ferry
A ferryctl needs to be installed for each cluster&amp;rsquo;s control node
https://github.com/ferry-proxy/ferryctl/releases
Initialize control plane # # execute on control plane ferryctl control-plane init Declares to the control plane which data plane needs to join # # execute on control plane to pre-join other data plane ferryctl control-plane pre-join direct cluster-1 If the network environment is more complex, please refer to Join Mode</description></item></channel></rss>